Contact

michael.j.smith690@gmail.co

www.linkedin.com/in/michael-s-36359521b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

PHP

Laravel

React.js

Certifications

AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate

Michael Smith

Full-stack Laravel/JavaScript Developer Queens

Summary

I am a seasoned and passionate full-stack web developer with 8+ years of experience, including 3 years of a senior web developer at TechNeed, one of New York's leading IT companies. In the past, I have designed and programmed websites for internal and external use, along with JavaScript-based responsive/dynamic web applications, using React, Vue, Angular, Node, Express, and various database. I have developed many PHP 7.x | 8.x / Laravel 5.x | 6 lts | 7.x based websites, providing support with content-based requests, custom forms, back-end (Laravel, Yii, Codelgniter, Symfony), and front-end (React, Angular, Vue, jQuery, TailwindCSS).

- Strong technical skills in application clustering, troubleshooting, and performance tuning.
- Aimed to create/collaborate web applications with purposeful and transformative effects.
- Genuine, carrying, profound, a great problem solver, humoristic, direct, motivating.
- Focuses on empowering and inspiring those that work with me.
- Looking to unlock potential, creativity, and a sense of purpose in people.
- Love solving problems and want to help change the world.

Experience

Perpetual:

Full-stack Web Developer (Laravel, Vue, React, Node) 2018 - 2021 (3 years)

Nyack, New York, United States

- Was able to test, and implement swagger UI docs/routes, for front-end use and back-end development
- Used RESTful API to put the data as time series and tabular format for local timestamp data manipulation and retrieval and storing it into PostgreSQL.
- Used Fast API, and some request library/decorators for faster development.

 Used AWS cloud desktop, for daily jobs, and Brazil Build for Cloud environment.

Techneeds

Senior Web Developer (Laravel, Yii, Symfony, Vue, Angular, React) July 2017 - June 2019 (2 years)

Hopewell, New Jersey, United States

- Designed and Developed SQL database structure with Laravel Framework using agile methodology.
- Developed project using Laravel, Vue, Oracle, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React.js, Express.js and Bootstrap.
- Used Fast API to dispatch front end JSON type schema, along with PHP/ SQL, for delivery of sql, csv files, and using mysql db.
- Involved in the complete Software Development Life Cycle including gathering Requirements, Analysis, Design, Implementation, Testing and Maintenance.
- Used PHPUnit for unit testing, and verification of functionality, during the beta phase of development.

Saffron Technology, an Intel company Web Developer (PHP, Laravel, Vue, Angular) 2014 - 2016 (2 years)

Fairfield, New Jersey, United States

- Developed views and templates with PHP and Laravel's view controller and templating language to create a user-friendly Website interface.
- Managed datasets using Panda data frames and Oracle-SQL, queried
 Oracle-SQL database queries from python using PHP-Oracle-SQL connector
 and Oracle-SQL db package to retrieve information.
- Taken part in software development life cycle (SDLC) of the tracking systems Requirements, Gathering, Analysis, Detail Design, Development, System Testing and User Acceptance Testing.
- Created Restful API's to integrate and enhance functionalities of the application.

Five Jars
Software Engineer (HTML, CSS, JavaScript)
2012 - 2013 (1 year)
Brooklyn, New York, United States

- Implemented user interface guidelines and standards throughout the development and maintenance of the Website using the HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery and VueJs.
- Design, involved in code reviews and wrote unit tests in PHP and Updated site with JavaScript, JQuery, Yii, Symfony, and SQL.
- Helped with the creation of a RESTful API using PHP-Laravel, integrating with Apache.

Education

Barnard College

Bachelor of Applied Science - BASc, Computer Science · (2006 - 2011)